RAY. ; After I killed them, I dropped the gun in the Thames,
殺死他們之後 我把槍扔進了泰晤士河
washed the residue off me hands in the bathroom of a Burger King,
在漢堡王的衛生間洗乾淨手上的血 （漢堡王是美國快餐三巨頭之一）
and walked home to await instructions.
然後回家等著下一次的任務
Shortly thereafter, the instructions came through.
不一會，命令來了
"Get the fuck out of London, youse dumb fucks.
「你們兩個蠢貨，滾出倫敦去
"Get to Bruges."
到布魯日去」
I didn't even know where Bruges fucking was.
我他媽布魯日在哪都不知道
It's in Belgium.
原來是在比利時
RAY. ; Bruges is a shithole.
布魯日真是個破地方
KEN. ; Bruges is not a shithole.
布魯日才不是個破地方
Bruges is a shithole.
布魯日就是個破地方
Ray, we've only just got off the fucking train.
雷，我們剛他媽下火車呢
Could we reserve judgment on Bruges until we've seen the fucking place?
你能等看到了布魯日再 說它破不破好吧？
I know it's gonna be a shithole.
不用看我就知道那是個破地方
(SOFTLY) Shithole.
破地方
I think you have a couple of rooms booked under Cranham and Blakely?
我想克蘭哈姆和布萊克裡是在您這 訂了兩個房間吧？
Yes. No, we have one room booked.
是的，哦不，只訂了一個房間
One twin room. Booked for two weeks.
一個雙人間，訂了兩周
Two weeks!
兩個星期？！
Do you have another room?
還有房間嗎？
No, I'm afraid we're fully booked.
沒有，很抱歉都被訂完了
With Christmas, everywhere is fully booked.
快聖誕節了，哪都客滿的
Okay.
好吧
It's very pretty.
真是美極了
I'm not being funny, we can't stay here.
跟你說吧，我們不能住在這
We've got to stay here until he rings.
我們在他來電話之前 必須得住在這
Well, what if he doesn't ring for two weeks?
喔，如果他兩周都沒給電話呢？
Then we stay here for two weeks.
那我們就在這呆兩周
For two weeks? In fucking Bruges? In a room like this?
呆兩周？在鳥不拉屎的布魯日？ 在這樣的房間裡？
With you? No way!
和你？門都沒有！
Ray, I really don't like to say this...
雷，我可不想說…
You really don't like to say what?
你不想說什麼？
Well... You know?
喔…你知道的
Fucking bring that up.
又提那事
Do you think this is good?
你覺得這樣好玩嗎？
Do I think what's good?
我覺得什麼好玩？
You know, going round in a boat, looking at stuff.
坐著船四處轉悠，東看看西瞅瞅
Yes, I do.
當然好玩了
It's called "sightseeing."
這就是「看風景」
Oh, look at that.
哦，看那個
It's a former hospital. From the 1100s.
那以前是個醫院 1100年建的
Bruges is the most well-preserved medieval town
很明顯布魯日是比利時保護的
in the whole of Belgium, apparently.
最好的中古世紀小鎮了
Coming up? What's up there?
- 上去吧？ - 那裡有什麼好看的？
The view.
風景啊
The view of what? The view of down here? I can see that from down here.
什麼的風景？俯瞰這破地方的風景？ 我在這一樣能看見
Ray, you're about the worst tourist in the whole world.
雷，你算是世界上最不 「稱職」的遊客了
Ken, I grew up in Dublin. I love Dublin.
肯，我是在都柏林長大的 我愛都柏林
If I'd grown up on a farm and was retarded, Bruges might impress me.
如果我是在一個農場裡長大的鄉巴佬 布魯日也許會讓我驚歎不已
But I didn't, so it doesn't.
但是我不是，所以我不會
Trying to get rid of me coins.
把我的硬幣先用完吧
3, 3.50, 4,
3，3.5，4
4.10, 4.20, 4.30, 4.40, 4.50, 4.60,
4.1，4.2，4.3 4.4，4.5，4.6
4.70,
4.7
4.80,
4.8
4.90.
4.9
Will you take 4.90?
就4.9歐元行嗎？
Entry is 5 euro.
門票是5歐元
Come on, man, it's only 10 cents.
拜託，大哥，就差10分而已
Happy in your work?
工作開心嗎？
Very happy.
相當開心
I like it here.
我喜歡這
MAN: Been to the top of the tower?
去過塔頂了嗎？
Yeah. Yeah, it's rubbish.
嗯，爛極了
It is? The guidebook says it's a "must-see".
是嗎？旅行指南說那是「必看」呢
Well, you lot ain't going up there.
喔，你們幾個可上不去
Pardon me? Why?
什麼意思？為什麼？
I mean, it's all windy stairs. I'm not being funny.
我是說，樓梯可承受不了太重的東西 我可不是說笑哦
What exactly are you trying to say?
你到底想說什麼？
What exactly am I trying to say?
我到底想說什麼？
Youse are a bunch of fucking elephants!
你們幾個肥豬太胖啦！
Right, you...
你…
Come on, leave it, fatty.
來啊，死肥豬
You know, you're just the rudest man. The rudest man!
知道嗎，你太無禮了！太粗魯了！
What's all that about?
怎麼了？
They're not going up there.
他們要上去
Hey, guys, I wouldn't go up there. It's really narrow.
嘿，夥計們，要是我就不上去了 樓梯小了
Screw you, motherfucker!
去死吧你，混蛋！
Americans, isn't it?
美國人，是吧？
Now, this is more like it. Proper holidays.
現在這樣才像樣嘛，專屬假期
One gay beer for my gay friend,
給我的同性戀朋友Gay啤 （德國的施密特世家釀造）
and one normal beer for me, because I am normal.
我的普通啤酒，因為我是正常的
This is the life.
這才叫生活
We're not staying here getting pissed.
我們呆在這裡可不是 為了喝的酩酊大醉
We are quietly sightseeing, like he says,
我們在這裡靜靜的看風景，就像他說的
and awaiting his call to see what we do next.
然後等著他的電話看下一步做什麼
This is my vote on what we should do.
我認為我們該這麼辦
We give it another day, two days, max.
我們再等一天，最多兩天
Then we check the papers again, and if there's still nothing in them,
然後看有沒有消息，如果還是沒有
we phone him and say, "Harry, thank you for the trip to Bruges,
我們就給他電話說，「哈里，謝謝你 把我們弄到布魯日來旅遊
"it's been very nice, all the old buildings and that,
這裡棒極了，古建築啊什麼的
"but we're coming back to London now, and hide out in a proper country,
不過我們現在回倫敦了 然後在鄉下渡假
"where it isn't all just fucking chocolates."
那裡最少不是哪都是巧克力」 （比利時巧克力很出名）
My vote would be we quietly sightsee, like he says,
我覺得我們安心的看風景 就像他說的
and await his call to see what we do next.
然後等他的電話看下一步做什麼
You don't even know we're here hiding out.
我們甚至不知道我們是否是來渡假的
What are you talking about?
你瞎說什麼呢？
You don't even know we're not here on a job.
我們甚至不知道我們是否來幹活的
What, on a job? Yeah.
- 什麼，幹活？ - 對
Here in Bruges?
- 在布魯日？
Here in Bruges, on a job? Yeah.
- 在布魯日，幹活？ - 對
Why? What did he actually say?
為什麼？他到底怎麼說的？
He didn't actually say anything.
他其實什麼也沒說
Then why do you think it might be? I don't think anything.
- 那你為什麼那麼想？ - 我沒有怎麼想
But it's a bit fucking over-elaborate, isn't it?
不過還真的有點小題大做哈，對吧？
"Go take him to hide out." "Go take him to hide out where?"
「帶他出去轉轉」 「帶他去哪？」
"Go take him to hide out in fucking Bruges."
「他媽的讓他到布魯日去」
You can hide out in Croydon.
你在克羅伊登也能渡假不是？ （英國大倫敦南側的一個區）
Hmm.
嗯
Or Coventry.
在考文垂也行 （英國英格蘭西米德蘭郡城市）
It is a bit over-elaborate.
是有點小題大做了
But we haven't got any guns.
不過我們還沒槍呢
Harry can get guns anywhere.
哈里在哪都能弄到槍的
He's not gonna ring tonight.
他今晚不會來電話的
Let's go out.
我們出去走走吧
Go out where? The pub.
- 去哪？ - 酒館啊
No!
不行！
Let's go out and have a look at some of the...
我們出去看看那些
All the old medieval buildings and that.
中古世紀的建築什麼的
Because I bet they look even better at night, all lit up.
晚上所有的燈都開著 我打賭它們會更漂亮的
Yes!
成功了！
That there is called the Gruuthuse Museum.
那是格呂德尤斯博物館
They all have funny names, don't they?
它們的名字都怪怪的，是吧？
Yes, Flemish.
對，那是佛蘭德斯語
In here it says, "The Belgians twice sheltered fugitive English Kings
這上面說，「比利時人在1471和1651年 兩次庇佑了
"from being murdered, 1471 and 1651."
逃亡的英國國王，使他們免遭殺害」
I used to hate history, didn't you?
我討厭歷史，你呢？
It's all just a load of stuff that's already happened.
只是記錄已經發生的事情的故紙堆
What are they doing over there?
他們在這幹嘛呢？
They're filming something. They're filming midgets!
他們在拍什麼 他們在拍侏儒呢！
Ray!
雷！
MAN: So, on this scene, you're supposed to walk like a little, tiny mouse, yeah?
那麼，在這劇情裡，你要像 一隻小巧玲瓏的老鼠一樣走路，明白？
Okay? Great.
明白了？好極了
Ray, come on, let's go.
雷，好了，走吧
My arse, "Let's go." They're filming midgets.
去你的，「我們走」 他們可是在拍侏儒呢
Oh, my God! Look at that girl.
哦，天！看那個女孩
She's gorgeous!
真是正點！
Ray, we're going right now.
雷，我們馬上走
Fuck off, are we!
走開，要走自己走！
This is the best bit of Bruges so far. You and your buildings.
這是來到布魯日以來讓我最開心的事情了 你是喜歡看建築哈
Hello.
好啊
Do you speak English? No.
- 你會說英語嗎？ - 不會
Yes, you do. Everybody does.
不，你會，誰都會的
What are you filming midgets for?
你們拍侏儒幹什麼啊？
It's a Dutch movie. It's a dream sequence.
是一部荷蘭電影，其中的一段夢境
It's a pastiche of Nicholas Roeg's Don't Look Now.
模仿尼古拉斯·羅格的《威尼斯疑魂》
Not a pastiche, but a...
不是模仿，拍這電影是為了…
A"homage" is too strong. A"nod of the head"?
說「表示敬意」可能太過了 那說「表示贊同」吧？
Wow, your English is very good.
哇噢，你的英語很好嘛
A lot of midgets tend to kill themselves.
很多侏儒都試圖自殺
A disproportionate amount.
人數多的難以想像
Herve Villechaize, off of Fantasy Island.
演《夢幻島》的赫維·維利伽茲
I think somebody off The Time Bandits.
還是《時光大盜》？
I suppose they must get really sad about, like,
我猜他們一定因為太矮小什麼的
being really little and that.
而非常難過
People looking at them and laughing at them.
大家看著他們，取笑他們
Calling them names. You know, "shortarse."
罵他們，你知道，「死矮子」什麼的
There's another famous midget I'm missing, but I can't remember.
我還記得一個著名的侏儒 不過名字我忘記了
It's not the R2-D2 man. No, he's still going.
不是說R2-D2（星球大戰裡的小機器人） 不，他在電影裡還活著呢
I hope your midget doesn't kill himself. Your dream sequence will be fucked.
我希望你那位侏儒不會尋短見 要不夢境你就拍不了了
He doesn't like being called a midget. He prefers "dwarf."
他不喜歡被人叫做侏儒 他喜歡「小矮人」
Well, this is exactly my point!
喔，這就是我想說的
People go around calling you a midget when you want to be called a dwarf.
大家都叫你侏儒 不過你卻想被人稱作「小矮人」
Of course you're gonna blow your head off!
當然你會抓狂了
My name's Ray. What's yours? Chloe.
- 我叫雷，你呢？ - 克洛伊
How did you get past the security man?
你是怎麼躲過保安的？
Getting past security men, it's sort of my job.
躲過保安可是我的工作
You're a shoplifter?
你是小偷？
(CHUCKLES) No, not a shoplifter.
不，才不是呢
It's a good joke, though.
不過你還真幽默
No.
不過我不是
I'll tell you what I am at dinner tomorrow night.
明天一起晚餐的時候 我就告訴你我是幹嘛的
Fuck.
完了
How fucking cool.
好極了
Mr. Blakely?
布萊克裡先生？
Yes. No, Mr. Cranham. No. Yes. Mr. Blakely. Yes.
是我，不，我是克蘭哈姆先生 不，是，布萊克裡先生，是的
You have a message.
你有留言
Shit!
見鬼！
HARRY. ; Number one, why aren't you in when I fucking told you to be in?
第一，為什麼讓你呆著你非得出去？
Number two, why doesn't this hotel have phones with fucking voicemail
第二，為什麼這旅店的電話 連語音信箱都沒有
and not I have to leave messages with the fucking receptionist?
我他媽的還得通過接待員留言？
Number three, you better fucking be in tomorrow night when I fucking call again
第三，你他媽的最好明晚 在我來電話的時候乖乖的呆在旅店裡
or there'll be fucking Hell to pay, I'm fucking telling you. Harry.
不然有你好看的 到時別他媽怪我沒和你說
Would you turn the fucking light off!
你他媽的把燈關了！
Sorry, Ken.
抱歉，肯
Keep the fucking noise down!
別他媽弄出那麼大動靜
Someone's in a mood.
有人心情不好啊
(SOFTLY) You'll never guess what.
你猜猜看剛才發生了什麼
Will you shut your fucking mouth, please, and go to sleep?
能請您老把嘴閉上 然後他媽的趕緊上床睡覺嗎？
Oh, sorry.
哦，抱歉
Except I've gotta take me contact lenses out.
不過我得先把隱形眼鏡拿出來
Altogether,
總的
I had
我喝了
five pints of beer and six bottles.
五品脫又六瓶啤酒
No. Six pints of beer and seven bottles.
不，六品脫又七瓶
And you know what? I'm not even pissed!
相信嗎？我尿都沒撒一次！
You'll never guess what, Ken.
你絕對猜不到剛才發生了什麼，肯
Ken, you'll never guess what. What?
- 你絕對猜不到剛才發生了什麼，肯 - 什麼？
Got a date for tomorrow night.
我明晚有約會啦
I'm very happy for you.
真替你感到高興
With a girl.
和一個女孩子呢
Can you turn the light off, please?
能勞駕您老把燈關了嗎？
Only been in Bruges one day, got a date with a girl in the film business,
在布魯日呆了一天，就和一個女孩約會了 她是電影行業的哦
the Belgian film business.
比利時電影業的
They're doing a film about a midget.
他們在拍關於侏儒的電影
Miss?
小姐？
Marie?
瑪麗小姐？
Sorry about the message last night. The man who left it is a bit of a...
昨晚的留言很抱歉了 留言的那人有點…
Well, he's a bit of a...
喔，他有點…
Cock?
混蛋？
Yes. He's a bit of a cock.
對，他有點混蛋
Morning.
早安
Harry called last night.
哈里昨晚來電話了
We missed him.
我們沒接到
Jeez, he swears a lot, doesn't he?
天，他一定「他媽的」很多次，是吧？
We're staying in tonight. Whatever happens.
無論如何今晚我們得呆在旅館了
Hmm.
嗯
Except...
除了…
Except "hmm" what?
除了「嗯」什麼？
Except only one of us needs to stay in, really.
除了我們只需要一個人留下就行了，真的
Uh-huh.
嗯哼
And which one of us would that be, now, Ray?
那是誰留下呢，雷？
I thought you didn't like Bruges.
我感覺你不喜歡布魯日啊
I don't like Bruges, it's a shithole.
我不喜歡布魯日，這個破地方
But I did already say I had a date with a Belgian lady
不過我已經說了我和比利時電影業
in the Belgian film business, which I did already say about before.
一個女孩子有約會了
Just don't get into any fucking trouble.
別惹什麼麻煩啊
We're keeping a low profile.
我們得低調
And this morning, and this afternoon,
還有，今天上午，今天下午
we are doing what I want to do.
我們做我想做的事情
Got it? Of course.
- 明白了？ - 知道了
Which, I presume, will involve culture.
我想，肯定是和文明什麼的啊有關了
Oh, we shall strike a balance between culture and fun.
哦，我們平衡一下文明和樂趣的
Somehow I believe, Ken, that the balance shall tip in the favor of culture.
不過我相信，肯，平衡會向文明傾斜的
Like a big, fat, fucking retarded, fucking black girl
就像蹺蹺板的一邊 他媽的是一個粗壯的黑人女孩
on a seesaw, opposite
對面呢
a dwarf.
是一個小矮子
(SOFTLY) Ray, did we or did we not agree
雷，我們是不是達成協議說
that if I let you go on your date tonight,
如果今晚我讓你去約會
we'd do the things I wanted to do today?
那白天就做我想做的事？
We are doing the things that you wanted to do today.
我們現在正在做你想做的事啊
And that we'd do them without you throwing a fucking moody,
那你現在他媽的亂發脾氣
like some 5-year-old who's dropped all his sweets?
像個5歲的孩子丟了自己的糖果似的？
I didn't agree to that.
這我可沒答應
I'll cheer up.
好吧，我會提起精神的
Up there, the top altar, is a phial
在那，最上面的聖壇，是一個藥瓶
brought back by a Flemish knight from the Crusades in the Holy Land.
那是一個佛蘭德斯騎士在 十字軍東征之時從聖地帶回來的
And that phial, do you know what it's said to contain?
那個藥瓶 你知道他們說裡面裝著什麼嗎？
No, what's it said to contain?
不知道，裝著什麼？
It's said to contain some drops of Jesus Christ's blood.
據說它裝著耶穌基督的幾滴血
Yeah, that's how this church got its name. Basilica of the Holy Blood.
嗯，這也是這教堂名字的由來 ——聖血教堂
Yeah. Yeah.
哦，哦
And this blood, right, though it's dried blood,
這血，對，儘管在千年來
at different times over many years, they say it turned back into liquid.
早已風乾，不過他們說 每次風乾之後，它又會變成液體
Turned back into liquid from dried blood.
從風乾的血重新變成液體的血
At various times of great
如此往復，不管外界
stress.
有多大的壓力
Yeah? Yeah.
- 是嗎？ - 是啊
So, yeah, I'm gonna go up in the queue and touch it, which is what you do.
那麼，嗯，我排隊上去摸摸它 你也去吧
Yeah? Yeah. You coming?
- 真的？ - 當然，你去嗎？
Do I have to?
我一定得去嗎？
Do you have to? Of course you don't have to.
你一定得去嗎？當然你不一定得去了
It's Jesus' fucking blood, isn't it? Of course you don't fucking have to!
那可是耶穌的血呢，對吧？ 你當然可以不用去了！
Of course you don't fucking have to!
你他媽的當然可以不用去了！
You little fucking cunt.
你個小笨蛋
RAY. ; Murder, Father.
殺人，神父
PRIEST. ; Why did you murder someone, Raymond?
你為何殺人，雷蒙？
For money, Father.
為了錢，神父
For money?
為了錢？
You murdered someone for money?
你殺人就為了錢？
Yes, Father.
是的，神父
Not out of anger, not out of nothing. For money.
不是出於憤怒，不是因為其他的任何原因 只是為了錢
Who did you murder for money, Raymond?
你為了錢殺了誰，雷蒙？
You, Father.
您，神父
I'm sorry?
什麼？
I said you, Father. What, are you deaf?
我說您，神父，怎麼，您耳背嗎？
Harry Waters says hello.
哈里·沃特斯向您問安
The little boy.
無辜的孩子
RAY: I quite like this one.
我喜歡這個
All the rest were rubbish by spastics, but this one's quite good.
其他的都是垃圾，不過這幅棒極了
What's that all about, then?
這說的是什麼呢？
It's Judgment Day, you know? Oh, yeah.
- 最後審判日，知道吧？ - 哦，知道
What's that then?
那又是什麼？
Well, it's, you know, the final day on Earth.
喔，那是，你知道 世界末日
When mankind will be judged for all the crimes they've committed and that.
那時人類將承擔起他們所犯的罪孽
And see who gets into Heaven and who gets into Hell and all that?
看誰能進入天堂，誰得墜入地獄？
Yeah.
對
And what's the other place?
還有什麼？
Purgatory.
煉獄
Purgatory?
煉獄？
Purgatory's kind of like the in-betweeny one.
煉獄是類似於中間物的地方
You weren't really shit, but you weren't all that great, either.
你不算太壞，但也稱不上好
Like Tottenham.
和托特納姆一樣 （倫敦北部最陰暗城市）
Do you believe in all that stuff, Ken?
你相信那些嗎，肯？
About Tottenham?
托特納姆？
The Last Judgment and the afterlife.
最後審判日和來生
Guilt and sins and
罪惡，犯罪
Hell and all that?
地獄啊，等等？
Um...
呃…
Well...
喔…
KEN: I don't know, Ray. I don't know what I believe.
我不知道，雷 我也不知道我相信什麼
The things you're taught as a child, they never really leave you, do they?
你小時候學到的東西 永遠都會伴隨著你，是吧？
So, like, I believe in trying to lead a good life.
比如，我想好好過日子
Like, if there's an old lady, carrying her shopping home,
如果有個老奶奶，要把買的東西弄回家
I don't try and help her carry her shopping, I don't go that far,
我不會試著幫她扛東西 我沒有那麼高尚
but I'll certainly hold the door open for her and that, and let her go out before me.
但是我會為她把門打開 讓她先出去
Yeah. And anyway, if you tried to help her carry her shopping,
嗯，不管怎麼樣 如果你想幫她扛東西
she'd probably think you were just trying to nick her shopping.
她也許會想你是想偷她的東西呢
Exactly. This is the world we live in today.
- 的確 - 這個世界就是這個樣子
At the same time as trying to lead a good life,
在想好好生活的同時
I have to reconcile myself with the fact that, yes, I have killed people.
我也得不斷的對我殺過人 自我麻醉，自我安慰
Not many people. Most of them were not very nice people.
不是很多，他們大部分都不算是好人
Apart from one person.
除了一個
Who's that?
誰？
This fellow, Danny Aliband's brother.
丹尼·艾裡班的兄弟
He was just trying to protect his brother. Like you or I would.
他只是想保護他的兄弟而已 就像你和我都會做的一樣
He was just a lollipop man.
他只是個護送員 （在學校門口護送小學生過馬路的人）
He came at me with a bottle. What are you gonna do?
他拿著個瓶子朝著我過來 你還能怎麼辦？
I shot him down.
我對著他開了槍
Hmm.
嗯
In my book, though, sorry, someone comes at you with a bottle,
不過在我看來，抱歉，如果有人 拿著瓶子想打你
that is a deadly weapon, he's gotta take the consequences.
那可是致命的武器 所以他得承受後果
I know that in my heart.
我心裡清楚得很
I also know that he was just trying to protect his brother, you know?
我還知道他只是 想保護他的兄弟，知道嗎？
I know. But a bottle, that can kill you.
我知道，但是一個瓶子，那能把你殺死的
It's a case of it's you or him.
不是你死就是他死
If he'd come at you with his bare hands, that'd be different.
如果他空手朝你殺過來 那就是兩碼事了
That wouldn't have been fair.
那就不公平了
Well, technically, your bare hands can kill somebody, too.
喔，從技術角度來講 你赤手空拳也能殺死人啊
They can be deadly weapons, too. I mean, what if he knew karate, say?
它們也能算是凶器呢 我是說，比如，萬一他會空手道呢？
You said he was a lollipop man.
你都說他是個護送員
He was a lollipop man.
他是個護送員
What's a lollipop man doing knowing fucking karate?
一個護送員他媽的幹嘛要會空手道？
I'm just saying.
我只是說說而已
How old was he? About 50.
- 他多大了？ - 50左右
What's a 50-year-old lollipop man doing knowing fucking karate?
一個50歲的護送員 他媽的幹嘛要會空手道？
What was he, a Chinese lollipop man?
他是誰，一個中國護送員？
Jesus, Ken, I'm trying to talk about...
天哪，肯，我是想說…
I know what you're trying to talk about.
我知道你要說什麼
I killed a little boy. You keep bringing up fucking lollipop men!
我殺了一個小孩子 你他媽的幹嘛不停的提什麼護送員！
You didn't mean to kill a little boy.
你不是故意殺死那個小孩子的啊
I know I didn't mean to.
我知道我不是有意的
But because of the choices I made and the course that I put into action,
但是因為我的選擇和我的所作所為
a little boy isn't here anymore.
一個小孩永遠的去了
And he'll never be here again.
他再也不會回來這了
I mean here in the world, not here in Belgium.
我說「這」指的是這個世界 不是說這裡
Well, he'll never be here in Belgium, either, will he?
喔，他也不能來這裡了，對吧？
I mean, he might have wanted to come here when he got older.
我是說，也許他長大了會想來這裡呢
I don't know why.
我不知道為什麼
And that's all because of me.
那都是因為我
He's dead because of me.
因為我他死了
And I'm trying to...
我試著…
I'm trying to get me head around it, but I can't.
我試著忘記，可我不能
I will always have killed that little boy.
就是我殺死了那個小孩子
That ain't ever going away. Ever.
這永遠都不會改變，永遠不會
Unless...
除非…
Maybe I go away.
除非我也死去
Don't even think like that.
別亂想了
You look good.
你看起來很帥了
What's it matter anyway?
有什麼關係呢？
So, what do you do, Raymond?
你是幹嘛的，雷蒙？
I shoot people for money.
我殺人賺錢
What kinds of people?
殺什麼樣的人呢？
Priests. Children. You know, the usual.
神父，孩子，你知道，平常人
Is there a lot of money to be made in that line of business?
這行當很賺錢嗎？
There is in priests. There isn't in children.
殺神父有錢賺 殺小孩就沒有了
So what is it you do, Chloe?
那你是幹什麼的，克洛伊？
I sell cocaine and heroin to Belgian film crews.
我賣可卡因和海洛因給 比利時電影工作人員
Do you?
是嗎？
Do I look like I do?
我看起來像嗎？
You do, actually.
嗯，挺像的
Do I look like I shoot people?
我看起來像會殺人嗎？
No.
不會殺人
Just children.
只殺孩子吧
Mmm-hmm.
嗯哼
I saw your midget today. Little prick didn't even say hello.
我今天看見了你的侏儒 他居然招呼都不打
Well, he's on a lot of ketamine.
喔，他用的克他命太多了吧 (一種高效麻醉劑)
What's that?
那是什麼？
Horse tranquilizer.
合成海洛英
A horse tranquilizer?
合成海洛英？
Where'd he get that? I sold it to him.
- 他從哪弄到的？ - 我賣給他的
You can't sell horse tranquilizers to a midget!
你怎麼能把合成海洛英賣給一個侏儒！
This movie, I think it's gonna be a very good one.
這電影，我想它會很成功的
There's never been a classic movie made in Bruges until now.
到現在在布魯日 還沒有拍出一部經典電影呢
Of course there hasn't, it's a shithole.
當然沒有了，這個破地方
Bruges is my hometown, Ray.
布魯日是我家鄉，雷
Well, it's still a shithole.
喔，它還是個破地方
It's not a shithole.
才不是呢
What? Even midgets have to take drugs to stick it.
是嗎？連侏儒都得嗑藥才能頂住
Okay.
好吧
So, you've insulted my hometown.
你侮辱了我的家鄉
You're doing very well, Raymond.
你做的很成功，雷蒙
Why don't you tell me some Belgian jokes while you're at it?
給我講幾個關於比利時的笑話吧？
I don't know any Belgian jokes.
我不知道哦
And if I did, I think I'd have the good sense not to...
如果我知道的話 我就不會…
Hey, hang on. Is Belgium where there were all those child abuse murders lately?
嘿，等等，比利時最近是不是很多 虐待孩子的兇手？
Then I do know a Belgian joke.
那我就知道一個笑話了
What's Belgium famous for?
比利時什麼出名啊？
Chocolates and child abuse.
巧克力和虐待兒童
And they only invented the chocolates to get to the kids.
他們發明那些巧克力 就是為了吸引那些孩子
What?
什麼？
One of the girls they murdered was a friend of mine.
他們殺死的其中一個 女孩是我的好朋友
I'm sorry, Chloe.
很抱歉，克洛伊
One of the girls they murdered wasn't a friend of mine.
他們殺死的其中一個 女孩不是我的好朋友
I just wanted to make you feel bad.
我只是想讓你鬱悶罷了
And it worked. Quite well.
還真有效，好極了
Fucking unbelievable.
真他媽沒教養
What's fucking unbelievable?
有什麼他媽的沒教養的？
Are you talking to me?
你是在和我說話？
(SOFTLY) He pauses, even though he should just hit the cunt.
他停頓了一下，儘管他只需要 打那個混蛋一頓
And he repeats.
他重複了一遍
Yes, I am talking to you. What's fucking unbelievable?
是的，我是和你說話 有什麼他媽的沒教養的？
Well, I'll tell you what's fucking unbelievable, shall I?
喔，我告訴你他媽的有什麼沒教養的 好吧？
Blowing cigarette smoke straight into myself and my girlfriend's face.
把煙直接噴在我和我女朋友的臉上
That's fucking unbelievable!
就這個他媽的沒教養！
This is the smoking section. I don't care if it's the smoking section.
- 這是吸煙區 - 我才不管
All right? She directed it right in my face, man.
好吧？她直接把煙吐在我臉上，夥計
I don't wanna die just because of your fucking arrogance. Uh-huh.
我可不想因為你的無知而早逝
Isn't that what the Vietnamese used to say?
越南人以前也就是這麼說的吧？
Vietnamese? What are you talking about, the Vietnamese?
越南人？你他媽說什麼呢？越南人？
That statement makes no fucking sense at all.
一點道理都沒有
Yes it does. The Vietnamese!
怎麼沒道理，越南人！
Well, saying it over and over ain't gonna make any more sense out of it.
喔，一遍接一遍的說 你還是在胡說八道
How does the Vietnamese have any relevance whatsoever
越南人和我以及我女朋友
to myself and my girlfriend having to breathe
得吸你女朋友的二手煙
your friend's cigarette smoke?
有個什麼狗屁聯繫？
Tell me how saying...
你告訴我…
That's for John Lennon, you Yankee fucking cunt!
這是替約翰·列儂打的！你個美國佬！ （列儂，披頭士成員，被美國人槍殺）
A bottle? No, don't bother.
瓶子？別費勁了
We're leaving.
我們走
I don't hit women! I would never hit a woman, Chloe!
我不打女人！ 我從來不打女人，克洛伊！
I'd hit a woman who was trying to hit me with a bottle!
我打女人是因為她拿著個瓶子想砸我！
That's different. That's self-defense, isn't it?
這就不同了，這是自衛，對吧？
Or a woman who could do karate.
要是她會空手道呢？
I'd never hit a woman generally, Chloe. Don't think that.
我從來不會打普通女人的，克洛伊 別亂想了
God, you're pretty.
神哪，你真美
I have to make a call.
我得打個電話
Oh, no.
哦，別那樣
You've gone off me, now, haven't you? Just because I hit that fucking cow.
你要離開我了，是吧？ 就因為我打了那個臭女人
Hello? HARRY. ; Where the fuck were you yesterday?
- 你好 - 你他媽昨天跑哪去了？
We just popped out for some dinner, Harry. We only popped out for half an hour.
我們出去吃晚餐了，就出去了半個小時
Yeah? What'd you have?
是嗎？吃什麼了？
For dinner? Yeah.
- 晚餐吃什麼了？ - 嗯
Pizza, at Pizza Hut.
披薩，在必勝客吃的
Was it nice?
好吃吧？
Yeah, it was all right. I don't know. It was Pizza Hut.
嗯，很不錯 我也不清楚，是必勝客嘛
The same as in England.
和英國的一樣
Well, that's globalization, isn't it? Is Ray there with you?
喔，這就是全球化啊，對吧？ 雷和你在一塊嗎？
He's in the toilet.
他在衛生間裡
Can he hear? No.
- 他能聽見嗎？ - 不能
What's he doing?
他在幹什麼？
What do you mean? Is he doing a wee or a poo?
- 什麼意思 - 他是小便還是大便？
I don't know, Harry, the door's closed.
我不知道，哈里，門關了
Send him out on an errand for half an hour, but don't make it sound suspicious.
讓他出去半個小時幹點什麼 不過別讓他起疑心
Ray? Why don't you go out down to the pub for half an hour?
雷？你想到酒館待個半個小時嗎？
Yeah, yeah, I know I said you couldn't,
嗯嗯，我知道我說過你不能出去
but might as well enjoy ourselves, eh?
不過還是得放鬆一下，是吧？
No, I don't know if they've got bowling anywhere. Could have a look.
不，我不知道有沒有保齡球館 你可以去看看
Yeah, see you.
好，回見
Yeah. He's gone.
好了，他走了
What'd you say to him?
你和他怎麼說？
I said, " Why don't you go have a drink, you say you've been cooped up?"
我說，「你出去喝一杯吧 你不是說這像坐牢嗎？」
What did he say? Said, yeah, he would.
- 他怎麼說？ - 他說，好的，他去
And he might go have a look to see if there's a bowling alley around.
他想看看能不能打保齡球
Was he just having a wee?
他剛才是在小便了？
Yeah, I think so. I assume so.
嗯，我想是吧，我猜是的
Sure he didn't mind?
確定他沒起疑？
No, he was glad to get out.
沒有，他很高興能出去
He's definitely gone?
他真的走了？
Yeah, yeah, he slammed the door.
嗯，一甩門出去了
That don't mean he's gone. Go check outside the door.
那不代表他走了 去門外看看
Harry, he's definitely gone.
哈里，他的確走了
You realize there are no bowling alleys in Bruges?
你知道布魯日沒有保齡球場嗎？
I realize that, Harry. The boy wanted to have a look anyway.
我知道，哈里，他還是想去找找看
What are they gonna have, a medieval fucking bowling alley?
他們會有什麼，一個他媽的 中古世紀的保齡球場？
As I say, I think he was just glad to get out and about.
我說了，他就是想出去走走
So, is he having a nice time, seeing all the canals and that?
那，他開心嗎，看那些運河什麼的？
I had a lovely time when I was there.
我去那的時候開心極了
All the canals and the old buildings and that.
那些運河啊，古老建築啊什麼的
When were you here?
你什麼時候來的？
When I was seven. Last happy holiday I fucking had.
我七歲的時候 他媽的我的最後一個快樂的假期
Have you been on a canal trip, yet? Yeah.
- 坐著船在運河上逛了嗎？ - 嗯
Have you been down, like, all the old cobbled streets and that?
在那些古老的大卵石街道上走過了吧？
Yeah.
嗯
It's like a fairytale, isn't it, that place? Yeah.
- 那裡就像是童話般美麗，是吧？ - 對
With the churches and that. They're Gothic. Yeah.
- 那些教堂，是中古世紀的吧
Is it Gothic?
- 是中古世紀的吧？ - 對
So he's having a really nice time?
那他過得很開心了？
Well, I'm having a really nice time.
喔，我在這裡過得很開心
I'm not sure if it's really his cup of tea.
我不知道他是否喜歡了
What?
什麼？
You know, I'm not sure if it's really his thing.
你知道，我不知道他是不是喜歡
What do you mean, "It's not really his thing"?
你說「他不太喜歡」是什麼意思？
What's that supposed to mean,
「他不太喜歡」是什麼意思？
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
那他媽的是什麼意思？
Nothing, Harry.
沒什麼，哈里
It's a fairytale fucking town, isn't it?
那裡他媽的是童話般的地方，是吧？
How can a fairytale town not be somebody's fucking thing?
一個童話般的小鎮他媽的怎麼可能 有人不喜歡？
How can all those canals and bridges and cobbled streets and those churches,
那些運河，石橋，石街，教堂
all that beautiful fucking fairytale stuff,
都他媽是童話裡的東西
how can that not be somebody's fucking thing, eh?
怎麼可能有人不喜歡，嗯？
What I think I meant to say was...
我想我的意思是…
Is the swan still there? Yeah, the swan's...
- 那天鵝還在那嗎？ - 在，那天鵝…
How can fucking swans not fucking be somebody's fucking thing, eh?
他媽的天鵝怎麼可能有人他媽的不喜歡？
How can that be?
那怎麼可能？
What I think I meant to say was,
我想我的意思是
when he first arrived, he wasn't quite sure about it.
剛到的時候 他不是很喜歡
You know, there's that big, dual carriageway when you get off the train?
你知道，剛下車你就能看見 一個大的，雙軌車道吧？
It mightn't have been here when you were here last, Harry.
哈里，可能你最後來的那次 那東西還沒有呢
Well, as soon as he got into, like, the old town proper,
喔，當他進入這個古老的小鎮之後
and he saw the canals and the bridges and, you know, the swans and that,
他看見那些運河，那些石橋 那些天鵝啊什麼的
well, he just fucking loved it then.
他他媽的就喜歡上了
Couldn't get enough of it, the medieval part of town.
怎麼都看不夠，那些中古世紀的東西
It was just that initial, dual carriageway thing sort of put him off for a second.
只是在開始，那些雙軌車道讓他有點不爽
Don't know if I remember a dual carriageway.
我不記得有沒有雙軌車道了
Must be recent.
一定最近才有的
Hasn't spoilt it, has it?
沒把那毀了吧，啊？
No, no, no, it's just that initial thing.
沒有沒有 只是一開始感覺不好而已
And you know what?
你知道嗎？
As we were walking through the streets,
當我們走在大街上
there was this sort of freezing fog hanging over everything,
一切都是霧濛濛的
and it made it look almost like a fairytale or something.
看起來就像是仙境一般
And he turned to me, do you know what he said?
他轉過頭對我說 你知道他說了什麼嗎？
What'd he say?
他說什麼？
He said, " Ken, I know I'm awake, but I feel like I'm in a dream."
他說，「肯，我知道我醒著 不過我感覺我是在做夢一樣。」
Yeah? He said that?
是嗎？他那麼說的？
Yeah.
嗯
Meaning, like, in a good dream?
是說，在一個美夢裡？
Yeah. Of course, like in a good dream.
嗯，當然，像是在做美夢
Oh, good. I'm glad he likes it there.
哦，好極了，我很高興他喜歡那裡
I'm glad we were able to give him something.
我很高興我們為他做點什麼
Something good and happy. Because he wasn't a bad kid, was he?
做讓他高興的事 因為他不是個壞孩子，是吧？
Huh?
哈？
He wasn't a bad kid, was he?
他不是個壞孩子，是吧？
Listen, take down this address. Raamstraat 17.
聽著，記下這個地址 拉姆斯查特17號
That's "Raam," like "Ram," but with an extra "a."
是「Raam」，發音和「Ram」一樣 不過多了一個「a」
Raamstraat 17.
拉姆斯查特17號
You got that?
記下了？
Yes, Raamstraat 17.
嗯，拉姆斯查特17號
Good. There'll be a man there tomorrow morning at 9.;00, his name's Yuri.
很好，明早9點會有人的 他叫宥利
Yuri. He'll give you the gun.
- 宥利 - 他會給你槍的
Ring me on the public phone at Jimmy Driscoll's
事情辦完了之後，用公用電話
about 3.;00 or 4.;00 tomorrow, after it's done.
在下午3點或者4點給 吉米·漢克斯家打電話找我
After what's done?
什麼事情辦完了之後？
Are you being thick?
你傻了還是怎麼了？
No. Listen, I like Ray.
- 我很好啊 - 聽著，我喜歡雷
He was a good bloke, but when it all comes down to it, you know,
他是個好小伙，不過直到那事發生之後
he blew the head off a little fucking kid. And you brought him in, Ken.
你知道，把一個小孩殺了 他就得接受懲罰，肯
So if the buck don't stop with him, where does it stop?
如果他不負責，誰來負責？
Ken?
肯？
It stops with me, Harry. That's an easy one.
我來負責，哈里 這很簡單
Look, don't get shirty, Ken.
聽著，別發火，肯
Listen, I'm just glad that I was able to do something for the boy before he went.
聽著，我很高興我能在他走之前 為他做點什麼
Do what for the boy?
為他做什麼？
You know, have him get to see Bruges.
你知道，讓他來看看布魯日
I'd like to go to see Bruges again before I die.
我也希望死之前能再去看看布魯日
What was it he said again about... Yeah, "It's like a dream."
他是怎麼說的來著…對了 「這就像是在做夢」
"I know I'm awake, but I feel like I'm in a dream."
「我知道我醒著 可是我感覺我是在做夢」
Yeah.
嗯
Give me a call when he's dead.
他死了之後給我打個電話
That's my fucking girlfriend, you asshole.
那是我女朋友，你個混蛋
Eirik, what are you doing?
埃裡克，你幹什麼呢？
Where are you from, fucker?
你是哪冒出來的，混蛋？
Ireland, originally.
愛爾蘭，祖籍
And you think it's okay to come over to Belgium
你覺得跑到比利時
and fuck another man's girl?
上別人的女人心安理得是嗎？
Look, I didn't know she had a boyfriend, all right?
聽著，我不知道她有男朋友，好吧？
And I haven't fucked her, anyway. Ask her. I'd only put me hand on it.
我也沒有上她，不信，問她 我只是摸了摸她而已
Eirik, put the gun down!
埃裡克，把槍放下
Get down on your knees and open your mouth.
跪下，把嘴張開
Don't start being silly.
別傻了
Get down on your...
跪…
Exactly at what point was it that all skinheads suddenly became poofs?
什麼時候光頭開始變得婆婆媽媽了？
Used to be, you were a skinhead,
你是小光頭的時候
you just went around beating up Pakistani 12-year-olds.
是不是只四處欺負 12歲大的巴基斯坦孩子
Now it seems a prerequisite to be a fucking bum-boy!
這就是你現在為什麼 是個癟三的主要原因吧？
That's not gonna help you, man.
那可幫不了你什麼忙，夥計
Ray, there's only blanks in that gun.
雷，那是空彈
Eirik, don't!
埃裡克，別！
Now who's the fucking bum-boy?
現在誰是癟三？
You, you fucking bum-boy!
你，你個癟三！
Chloe, what exactly is going on here?
克洛伊，這到底是怎麼回事？
I can't see!
我看不見了！我看不見了！
Of course you can't fucking see! I just shot a blank in your fucking eyes!
你他媽的當然看不見了！ 我剛剛對著你的眼睛開了空槍！
Is this fella your boyfriend? No. I mean, he used to be.
- 這傢伙是你男朋友嗎？ - 不是，我是說，他曾經是
Well, what's he doing here?
喔，那他來這幹什麼？
We... We rob tourists, sometimes.
我們…我們搶劫遊客，有時候
I fucking knew it was too good to be true!
他媽的我就知道天下沒這麼好的事！
I knew you'd have never shagged me, normally.
我就知道正常情況下 你才不可能和我上床呢！
No! That's not true, I...
不！那是真的，我…
I called it off tonight. I told him not to come tonight.
我說了今晚不行動了 我讓他今晚別過來了
Why did you come tonight?
你今晚幹嘛過來？
EIRIK: Chloe, I can't see, I swear it!
克洛伊，我看不見，真的！
Stop whingeing like a big gay baby.
別像個娘們似的呼天搶地的
I haven't had a shag in months!
我好幾個月沒和人上過床了！
I can't see out of this eye, Chloe! I have to go to the hospital!
我這個眼睛看不見了，克洛伊！ 我得去醫院！
I'll drive you.
我開車送你
Great! Now the whole night's ruined!
好極了！整個晚上都毀了！
No!
不！
You can stay if you want. I just don't know how long I'll be.
你可以待在這 不過我不知道我什麼時候能回來
I just knew someone like you would never like someone like me.
我就知道你這樣的人 是不可能喜歡上我這樣的人的
I just knew. What do you mean, someone like me?
- 我就知道 - 你說像我這樣的人，是什麼意思？
You know, someone nice.
你知道，好人
Call me. Please.
給我電話，一定哦
EIRIK: Chloe!
克洛伊
Cha-ching!
賺了！
Have you got some sort of problem?
你有什麼病是嗎？
No, no problem.
不，沒有
Four beers in 20 minutes. No problem.
20分鐘要了四杯啤酒 沒問題
Fuck off.
多管閒事
JIMMY: Beer and a red wine.
來杯啤酒和紅酒
I'll be back.
我一會就回來
How's the movie going?
電影拍的怎麼樣了？
It's a jumped-up Eurotrash piece of rip-off fucking bullshit.
純粹他媽的一部自以為是 東施效顰模仿歐洲風格的破東西
Like, in a bad way?
不好？
Your girlfriend's very pretty.
你女朋友相當漂亮啊
She ain't my girlfriend. She's a prostitute I just picked up.
她不是我女朋友 她只是我剛找來的妓女
Didn't know there were any prostitutes in Bruges.
我不知道布魯日還有妓女
You just have to look in the right places.
你得找對地方才行
Brothels are good.
妓院裡就很多
Well, you've picked up a very pretty prostitute.
喔，那你找到了一個很好的妓女
Thank you.
謝謝
You from the States?
你是美國來的？
Yeah.
嗯
But don't hold it against me.
不過別因此對我有偏見哈
I'll try not to.
盡量吧
Just try not to say anything too loud or crass.
說話別太大聲或者太粗魯就行了
Hey-ho. Drowning your sorrows, huh?
嘿，借酒澆愁呢？
What sorrows? You know, being a sad, old, ugly little man.
- 什麼愁？ - 看，你是個傷心，蒼老而醜陋的小矮人
One gay beer, please.
來杯Gay啤
How'd your date go?
你的約會怎麼樣？
My date involved two instances of extreme violence.
我的約會分成兩個極其暴力的部分
One instance of her hand on my cock and my finger up her thing,
一部分是她的手放在我的傢伙上 我的手指在她的上面
which lasted all too briefly. Isn't that always the way?
不過春宵恨短，是不是都是這樣呢？
One instance of me stealing five grams of her very-high-quality cocaine,
另外一部分 是我偷走了她五克高質量的可卡因
and one instance of me blinding a poofy little skinhead.
還有我把一個光頭娘娘腔整瞎了
So, all in all, my evening pretty much balanced out fine.
所以，總的來說，今晚還是挺好的
You got five grams of coke?
你有五克可卡因？
I've got four grams on me and one gram in me,
只剩四克——那一克我已經享用完了
which is why me heart is going like the clappers,
這就是我的心臟快的像拍板一樣
as if I'm about to have a heart attack.
好似要心臟病發了
So if I collapse any minute now, please remember to tell the doctors
所以如果我倒下了，記得告訴醫生
that it might have something to do with the coke.
很可能和可卡因有關係
Give us a gram, then.
給我們一克吧
I thought you were laying off, because it makes you depressed?
我以為你不吸了呢，因為那會 讓你感覺很沮喪？
You know what? Right now, I don't really give a fuck.
知道嗎？現在我才不在乎呢
Why didn't you wave hello to me today when I waved hello to you today?
今天我和你揮手你怎麼不理我啊？
I was on a very strong horse tranquilizer today.
我今天嗑了太多合成海洛英
I wasn't waving hello to anybody, except maybe to a horse.
我和誰都沒打招呼，除了藥
Huh? What are you talking about?
呃？你說什麼呢？
Just horseshit.
沒什麼
You from America?
你是美國來的？
Yeah. But don't hold it against me.
嗯，不過不要因此看低我
Well, that's for me to decide, isn't it?
喔，這是我的事，對吧？
Are you from America, too?
你也是美國來的嗎？
No, I'm from Amsterdam.
不是，我是阿姆斯特丹來的
(SCOFFS) Amsterdam.
阿姆斯特丹
Amsterdam is just a load of bloody prostitutes, isn't it?
阿姆斯特丹那都是妓女是嗎？
Yes. That's why I came to Bruges.
是的，這就是我來布魯日的原因
I thought I'd get a better price for my pussy here.
在這裡我也許能賣個好價錢
Huh?
哈？
You two are weird.
你們兩個真怪
Would you like some cocaine?
想來點可卡因嗎？
I've also got some acid and some ecstasy.
我還有迷幻藥和快樂丸
Herve Villechaize, I know, did.
赫維·維利伽茲，我知道，真的
The dwarf off, I think, The Time Bandits, did.
是，我想想，《時光大盜》裡的小矮子
Lots of midgets...
很多矮人…
Dwarves, top themselves.
矮子們，自殺了
Hmm. Shitloads.
嗯，很多
Would you ever think about it?
你想過沒有？
Huh?
什麼？
Would you ever think about killing yourself because you're a midget?
你有沒有因為自己是侏儒而想自殺？
Fuck, man! What kind of question is that?
靠，夥計！這算是什麼問題？
We're just chatting, aren't we?
聊天而已，不是嗎？
See, Ken, this is the kind of hotel Harry should have put us in.
看，肯，哈里應該給我們訂這樣的 旅館才對
A five-star, with prostitutes in.
五星級，還有妓女
You know, sometimes, I think Harry doesn't even give a shit about us at all.
你知道，有時候 我想哈里壓根就不在乎我們
Has he still not called?
他還沒有來電話嗎？
No. Still hasn't called.
沒有，還沒
No news is good news, eh?
沒有消息就是好消息，對吧？
RAY: Hmm.
嗯
Who's she?
她是誰？
JIMMY: There's gonna be a war, man.
將會有場戰爭的，夥計
I can see it.
我能預見到
There's gonna be a war between the blacks and between the whites.
黑人和白人之間將會有一場戰爭
You ain't even gonna need a uniform no more.
甚至不用穿上軍裝
This ain't gonna be a war where you pick your side.
這場戰爭你沒法選擇你站在哪邊
Your side's already picked for you.
你站在哪邊早就命中注定了
And I know whose side I'm fighting on. I'm fighting with the blacks.
我知道我站在哪邊 我和黑人一起戰鬥
The whites are gonna get their heads kicked in!
我們要把白人打的抱頭鼠竄！
JIMMY: You don't decide this shit, man.
這不是你來決定的，夥計
Well, who are the half-castes gonna fight with?
喔，那些混血兒站在哪邊呢？
The blacks, man. That's obvious.
黑人，夥計，很明顯的嘛
But what about the Pakistanis?
巴基斯坦人呢？
The blacks. What about...
- 黑人 - 那…
Think of a hard one.
想個難的
What about the Vietnamese?
越南人呢？
The blacks!
黑人！
Well, I'm definitely fighting with the blacks if they've got the Vietnamese.
喔，如果黑人有越南人助陣的話 那我也加入
So, hang on.
等等
Would all of the white midgets in the world be fighting
世界上所有的白矮人都會和
against all the black midgets in the world?
黑矮人戰鬥嘍？
Yeah.
是的
That would make a good film!
那要拍成電影一定是經典！
You don't know how much shit I've had to take off of black midgets, man.
你是不知道，我以前被黑矮人欺負的多慘
That's...
這個…
Undeniably true.
你不說我也知道
See, Jimmy,
看，吉米
my wife was black.
我妻子是黑人
And I loved her very much.
我很愛她
And in 1976, she was murdered by a white man.
1976年，她被一個白人殺害了
So, where the fuck am I supposed to stand in all this blood and carnage?
那麼，我他媽的 在這血雨腥風中該站在哪邊？
Did they get the guy who did it?
抓到那個兇手了嗎？
A friend of mine got him.
我的一個朋友抓住了他
Harry Waters got him.
哈里·沃特斯抓到了
So tell me, Jim, whose side do I fight on in this wonderful war?
那告訴我，吉姆 我這場戰爭裡該站在哪邊？
I think you need to weigh up all your options
我想你需要權衡所有的因素
and let your conscience decide, Ken.
然後讓你的良心去決定，肯
Two manky hookers and a racist dwarf.
兩個骯髒的妓女和一個種族主義侏儒
I think I'm heading home.
我還是回家好了
Yeah. I think I'll come with you.
嗯，我和你一起走
What's... Back off, shorty!
走開，矮子
You don't know karate.
你可不會空手道
Don't say you didn't have it coming.
別說這不是你罪有應得！
Shortarse!
死矮子！
Meeting Yuri.
我找宥利
Yes, I'm Yuri.
嗯，我就是
Mr. Waters said that might be necessary.
沃特斯先生說可能用得上
There are a lot of alcoves in the Koningin Astrid Park.
阿斯特麗德公園有很多幽僻的地方
You use this word, "alcoves"?
你用「幽僻的地方」這個單詞吧？
"Alcoves"? Yes. Sometimes.
「幽僻的地方」？用，有時候
There are not many people around in these alcoves in Christmastime.
聖誕節的時候那裡人都很少
If I were to murder a man, I would murder him here.
如果我要殺人，我會在哪兒殺他
Are you sure this is the right word, "alcoves"?
你確定你沒用錯詞，「幽僻的地方」？
"Alcoves," yes. It's kind of like "nooks and crannies."
「幽僻的地方」，嗯 和「隱蔽的地方」差不多的意思
"Nooks and crannies," yes. Perhaps this would be more accurate.
「隱蔽的地方」，嗯，也許這更確切一點
"Nooks and crannies," rather than "alcoves." Yeah.
「隱蔽的地方」比「幽僻的地方」更好，嗯
You are going to do it, aren't you? Mr. Waters will be very disappointed...
你會殺了他的，對吧？ 要不沃特斯先生會很失望…
Of course I'm going to fucking do it.
我他媽的當然會了
It's what I do.
這就是我的工作
Your friend was behaving rather oddly this morning.
你朋友今天可有點古怪
Oddly? How?
古怪？怎麼了？
Well, he asked me about the baby, and if I wanted a boy or a girl.
喔，他問我懷孕的事 問我是想要男孩還是女孩
I said I didn't mind as long as it's healthy, of course.
當然，我說只要健健康康的 男女都無所謂了
But then he gave me 200 euros to give to the baby.
但是然後他就給我200歐元 說是給孩子的
I refused, obviously, but he was quite insistent.
我當然拒絕了，但是他一直堅持
Would you give it back to him when you see him?
你見到他請把錢還他好嗎？
I don't want to appear ungrateful, but it seemed like all the money he had.
我不是不領情 只是看起來這是他身上所有的錢了
Do you know where he is now? He said he was going to the park.
- 你知道他去哪了嗎？ - 他說他去公園走走
Sorry, Ray.
對不住了，雷
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Ray, don't!
雷，不要！
Fucking hell! Where the fuck did you come from?
見鬼！你他媽從哪冒出來的？
I was behind the thing. What the fuck are you doing, Ray?
我剛才躲在那後面 你他媽的這是幹什麼呢，雷？
What the fuck are you doing?
你他媽又是想幹什麼？
Nothing.
沒什麼
Oh, my God!
哦，天哪
You were gonna kill me. No, I wasn't.
- 你要殺我 - 不，不是
You were gonna kill yourself!
你差點自殺了！
I'm allowed to.
我有這個權利啊
No, you're not!
不，你沒有
What?
什麼？
I'm not allowed to and you are? How's that fair?
我不能殺我，你卻能殺我？ 這是哪門子道理？
Can we go somewhere and talk about this, please?
找個地方坐下來談談，好吧？
I wasn't gonna go through with it, Ray.
我下不了手，雷
You fucking looked like you were gonna go fucking through with it.
可你他媽的看起來就要得手了呢
Where'd you get that gun?
槍是哪裡來的？
A friend of Harry's.
哈里的朋友的
Fuck, man.
靠，夥計
Let me see it.
我看看
Silencer, too.
還有消音器哈
Nice.
很好
Mine's a bloody girl's gun.
我的他媽的是女式手槍
I'm keeping it. Pardon me?
- 我來保管了 - 什麼？
Give me me gun back. You're not getting it back.
- 把槍還我 - 不還
You're a suicide case.
你有自殺傾向
And you were trying to shoot me in the fucking head.
你他媽還想一槍把我崩了呢
You're not getting that gun back.
反正槍不會給你的
A great day this has turned out to be.
今天看來還真有趣了
I'm suicidal, me mate tries to kill me,
我想自殺，我的搭檔想殺我
me gun gets nicked and we're still in fucking Bruges.
我的槍被沒收了，我們他媽的還在布魯日
Listen, I'm gonna give you some money and put you on a train somewhere.
聽著，我給你點錢然後送你上火車
Back to England?
回英國？
You can't go back to England, Ray. You'd be a dead man!
你可不能會英國了，雷 回去你就死定了
(CRYING) I want to be a dead man.
我倒是真想死呢
Have you been missing something?
你是不是忘了這茬兒了？
You don't want to be a dead man, Ray.
你不會想死的，雷
I killed a little boy!
我殺死了一個小男孩
Then save the next little boy.
那下一次救一個小男孩
Just go away somewhere,
走吧
get out of this business and try to do something good.
別做這行當了，做些好事
You're not gonna help anybody dead.
人死不能復生
bring that boy back.
那個孩子已經回不來了
But you might save the next one.
但是下一次你也許能救誰
What am I gonna be, a doctor?
我要當什麼，醫生？
You need exams.
得考試呢
Do anything, Ray. Do anything.
做什麼都行，雷，什麼都行
RAY: What a wanker!
真賤！
He said this whole trip,
他說這次旅行
this whole being in Bruges thing,
來布魯日旅行
was just to give you one last, joyful memory before you died.
都只是想在你死之前給你 一段美好的回憶
In Bruges?
在布魯日？
The Bahamas, maybe.
去巴哈馬還差不多！ （旅遊勝地，人稱「加勒比蘇黎世」）
Why fucking Bruges?
為什麼要到布魯日來？
I suppose it's cheaper.
我想可能是更便宜吧
The rest of the acid and the ecstasy.
這是剩下的迷幻藥和快樂丸
Can I have me gun back, please?
能把槍給我嗎？
What am I gonna do, Ken?
我該做什麼呢，肯？
What am I gonna do? Just keep moving.
- 我該做什麼？ - 繼續生活就行了
Keep on moving.
繼續生活
Try not to think about it.
別想太多
Learn a new language, maybe?
或許學一門新的語言？
Sure, I can hardly do English.
我是太依賴英語了
That's one thing I like about Europe, though.
不過這是我喜歡歐洲的一個原因
You don't have to learn any of their languages.
你不用學他們的語言
Just forget about home for a while.
暫時忘記一些事情吧
See how the land lies in six years, seven years.
六七年之後再看形勢怎麼樣
Seven years is not that long.
七年也沒想像中久
It's longer than that boy got.
那小男孩七歲都沒有呢
Me first fucking job.
我第一次殺人任務呢
Great hitman I turned out to be.
看來我是個超級職業殺手呢
Some people just aren't cut out for it, Ray.
有些人不是幹這行的料，雷
Are you?
你是嗎？
When are you going back to England?
你什麼時候回英國？
I'll head back in a couple of hours or something.
我過幾個小時就回
Harry's not gonna be mad at you, is he? For letting me go?
哈里會對你大發雷霆的，對吧？ 你都把我放了
I'll sort out Harry.
我會揍他的
Just tell him I'll have probably killed meself in a fortnight, anyway.
你告訴他也許 我兩周內就自殺了也不一定
You won't, will you, Ray?
你不會的，是吧，雷？
Harry? It's Ken.
哈里？我是肯
Listen to this noise.
聽這聲音
Do you know what that is?
知道是什麼嗎？
Yeah, I know you know it's a train. Do you know what train?
嗯，我知道你知道那是火車聲 你知道是什麼火車嗎？
Well, it's a train that Ray just got on, and he's alive and he's well,
喔，那是雷剛上的那趟火車 他活著，好好的
and he doesn't know where he's going and neither do I.
他不知道火車去哪 我也不知道
So if you need to do your worst, do your worst.
你愛怎麼的怎麼的吧，我奉陪到底
You've got the address of the hotel. I'll be here waiting.
你已經知道旅館的地址了 我在那恭候大駕
Because I've got to quite like Bruges, now.
我現在非常喜歡布魯日
It's like a fucking fairytale or something.
這裡他媽的簡直就像是仙境呢
Harry.
哈里
Harry!
哈里！
What?
怎麼？
It's an inanimate fucking object.
那他媽只是沒有生命的東西！
You're an inanimate fucking object!
你他媽只是沒有生命的東西！
Now, you lot be good for your mummy and lmamoto, okay?
你們乖乖的聽媽媽和今本小姐的話
'Cause Daddy's got to go away for a few days.
爸爸要出去幾天
Where are you going?
你去哪？
I've got to go to Bruges.
布魯日
Bruges? Where's that?
布魯日？在哪？
It's in Belgium.
比利時
Why would anybody have to go to Belgium?
幹嘛要去比利時呢？
'Cause I've got to sort something out.
我有些事情得處理
Is it something to do with the phone?
和剛才的電話有關嗎？
It's something to do with Ken.
和肯有關
It's a matter of honor.
事關榮譽
Well, it ain't gonna be dangerous, is it?
喔，那會很危險了，是吧？
Well, of course it's gonna be dangerous if it's a matter of fucking honor!
事關榮譽他媽的當然會很危險了！
You are bringing the fellas with you?
你帶夥計過去嗎？
Tell me you're bringing the fellas with you.
告訴我說你會帶夥計過去！
Harry.
哈里
I'm sorry for calling you an inanimate object.
我很抱歉罵你沒生命的東西
I was upset.
我當時太沮喪了
You're Irish? Yes.
- 你是愛爾蘭人？ - 是的
What is your name?
你叫什麼？
Derek Perlurrl.
德裡克，佩，呃，魯爾
You hit the Canadian.
你打了加拿大人
L"heet" the Canadian? I don't know what you're talking about.
我「熱烈的」加拿大人？ 你說什麼呢？
That's him! That's the motherfucker.
就是他，就是那個混蛋
You hit the Canadian, yeah?
你打了加拿大人，是吧？
Canadian? Shit.
加拿大人？靠
We're taking you back to Bruges. Brilliant.
- 我們把你帶回布魯日 - 好極了
Aye aye.
船長好啊
YURl: Take your pick, Mr. Waters.
自己挑吧，沃特斯先生
(CHUCKLES) An Uzi?
烏茲拉衝鋒鎗？
I'm not from South Central Los fucking Angeles.
我他媽可不是洛杉磯南部中心來的
I didn't come here to shoot 20 black 10-year-olds in a fucking drive-by.
我可不是要開著車 射殺20個10歲大的黑人小孩
I want a normal gun for a normal person.
我要殺一個普通人 所以只要一把普通的槍
I knew he wouldn't kill the guy.
我知道他不會殺那個人的
I could see it in his eyes when I was telling him about the alcoves.
但我和他說「幽僻的地方」的時候我能 從他的眼睛裡看出來
About the what? The alcoves.
- 說什麼？ - 幽僻的地方
The alcoves in the Koningin Astrid Park.
阿斯特麗德公園裡幽僻的地方
Oh, I also have some dumdums.
我還有些達姆彈 （殺傷力極大的一種子彈）
You use this word, "dumdums"? The bullets that make the head explode?
你說「達姆彈」嗎？ 那種能把人頭打爆的子彈？
Dumdums, yeah.
達姆彈，嗯
Would you like some of these dumdums?
想要一些嗎？
I know I shouldn't,
我知道我不應該要的
but I will.
不過我還是要了
Motherfucker.
混蛋
Is he talking to me?
他是在和我說話嗎？
No, Eirik's on your side, Mr. Waters.
不，埃裡克可是和你一邊的，沃特斯先生
Your young friend blinded him last night.
你的小弟昨晚把他弄瞎了
Ray did?
雷干的？
I was trying to rob him and he took my gun from me.
我想搶劫他，他把我的槍搶走了
And the gun was full of blanks,
那槍裡都是空彈
and he shot the blank into my eye.
他就對著我開空槍
And now, I cannot see from this eye ever again, the doctors say.
現在好了 醫生說我這隻眼睛再也看不見了
Well, to be honest, it sounds like it was all your fault.
喔，說實話 聽起來你是自作自受呢
What?
什麼？
I mean, basically, if you're robbing a man and you're only carrying blanks,
我是說，如果你要搶人槍卻空彈
and you allow your gun to be taken off you,
槍還被搶走了
and you allow yourself to be shot in the eye with a blank,
你還讓他對著你的眼睛開空槍
for which I assume the person has to get quite close to you, then,
我想他離你很近吧
yeah, really, it's all your fault for being such a poof.
所以只能說你太婦人之仁，自作自受
So why don't you stop whingeing and cheer the fuck up?
你他媽還是別嘰嘰歪歪發牢騷了 打起精神來吧
YURl: Eirik, I really wouldn't respond.
埃裡克，要是我可不會理他
I thought you wanted the guy dead?
你不是想殺了那傢伙嗎？
I do want the guy dead. I want him fucking crucified.
我的確也想殺了他 我想把他五馬分屍，千刀萬剮
But it don't change the fact that he stitched you up like a blind, little gay boy.
但是那都無法改變他把你弄成瞎子 這個事實，小娘們
Does it?
是吧？
Thanks for the gun, Yuri.
謝謝你的槍了，宥利
Well?
有什麼要說的？
The boy is suicidal, Harry.
他想自殺呢，哈里
He's a walking dead man.
他只是行屍走肉罷了
Keeps going on about Hell and purgatory...
不斷的在地獄和煉獄之間遊走
When I phoned you yesterday, did I ask you,
昨天我打電話的時候，我有沒有和你說
"Ken, will you do me a favor and become Ray's psychiatrist, please?"
「肯，能幫我勸勸雷嗎？」
No. What I think I asked you was, " Could you go blow his fucking head off for me?"
沒有！ 我是和你說「你能幫我宰了他嗎？」
"He's suicidal"?
「他要自殺？」
I'm suicidal. You're suicidal. Everybody's fucking suicidal!
我還要自殺呢！你也自殺得了！ 大家都自殺得了！
We don't all keep going on about it!
可有誰真自殺了！
Has he killed himself yet? No. So he's not fucking suicidal, is he?
他殺死自己了嗎？沒有 所以他他媽沒自殺，對吧？
He put a loaded gun to his head this morning. I stopped him.
他把裝彈的槍頂著自己的頭 我阻止了他
He... What? This gets fucking worse!
他…什麼？越來越不像話了！
We were down in the park...
我們在公園裡…
Let me get this right. You were down in the park?
等等，你們去公園了？
What's that got to do with fucking anything?
去公園干屁？
Let me get this right. Not only have you refused to kill the boy,
我沒弄錯的話，你不但不殺他
you've even stopped the boy from killing himself,
還阻止他自殺
which would have solved my problem,
殺了他就能解決我的難題了
solved your problem,
也能解決你的
which sounds like it would've solved the boy's problem.
聽起來也能讓他解脫
It wouldn't have solved his problem.
那不會讓他解脫的
Ken, if I had killed a little kid, accidentally or otherwise,
肯，如果我殺死了一個小孩 不管是意外還是怎麼的
I wouldn't have thought twice.
我一點都不會猶豫
I'd have killed myself on the fucking spot. On the fucking spot.
我立馬就自殺，立馬自殺！
I'd have stuck the gun in me mouth on the fucking spot!
我會立馬把槍塞進嘴裡
That's you, Harry. The boy has the capacity to change.
那是你，哈里，那個孩子還有機會
The boy has the capacity to do something decent with his life.
他還有能力和機會做些好事
Excuse me, Ken. I have the capacity to change.
抱歉，肯，我才有機會
Yeah, you do. You've the capacity to get fucking worse!
嗯，你有，你只有讓事情變壞的能力
Yeah, now I'm getting down to it!
嗯，現在我明白了
Harry, let's face it.
哈里，我們還是面對現實吧
And I'm not being funny, I mean no disrespect,
我不是開玩笑，也不是對你不敬
but you're a cunt.
但是你是個混蛋！
You're a cunt now, you've always been a cunt.
你現在是個混蛋，你一直都是！
And the only thing that's gonna change is you're gonna become an even bigger cunt.
唯一會改變的事情就是 你會變得越來越混蛋
Maybe have some more cunt kids.
也許還會有更多的混蛋孩子
Leave my kids fucking out of it. What have they done?
別把我的孩子扯進來 他們難道做了什麼壞事？
You fucking retract that bit about my cunt fucking kids!
你他媽的趕緊 收回關於我混蛋孩子的那句話！
I retract that bit about your cunt fucking kids.
我收回關於你混蛋孩子的那句話！
Insulting my fucking kids! That's going overboard, mate!
敢侮辱我的孩子！ 你這就太過份了，夥計！
I retracted it, didn't I?
我不是收回了，是吧？
Still leaves you being a cunt.
不過你他媽的依然是個混蛋
Yeah, I fucking got that.
嗯，我知道
Where's Ray now?
雷現在在哪？
Oh, right about now, Ray is in one or other
哦，現在啊
of the one million towns in mainland Europe it's possible to be in, other than here.
雷可能在成千上萬個歐洲大陸城市的 任何一個裡，反正不在這
I'll get all the money back to you soon as I get through to me friend.
我找到我朋友之後一定把錢都還你
It's not a problem, Raymond.
沒事的，雷蒙
And I'll get all your acid and your ecstasy back to you, too.
還有把迷幻藥和快樂丸也都還你
English humor!
英式幽默！
I'm assuming you've got your gun on you.
我想你身上帶著槍吧？
That Yuri bloke's a funny fella, isn't he?
那個叫宥利的是個有趣的小子，是吧？
He does yoga.
他練瑜伽
"The alcoves."
「幽僻的地方」
Was he going on to you about the alcoves?
他和你說幽僻的地方了？
"The alcoves in the Koningin Astrid Park."
阿斯特麗德公園裡幽僻的地方
Harry, I know you gotta do what you gotta do.
哈里，我知道你得做你該做的事
It's a bit crowded round here, you know?
這裡人太多了，是吧？
Well, I'm not gonna have a shootout
喔，我可沒打算
in the middle of a thousand fucking Belgians, am I?
在一群比利時人當中開槍
Not to mention the other nationalities, just on their holidays.
別說還有好多別的國家來度假的人
Hmm.
嗯
To see the swans and the Gothic and all the fairytale stuff, eh?
來看天鵝和教堂還有仙境什麼的？
Are you trying to fucking wind me up? No, Harry.
- 你是想激怒我是嗎？ - 不，哈里
On top of calling me a cunt and calling me kids cunts.
叫我混蛋也就算了 還說我的孩子也是混蛋
I might just have to fucking shoot you right here.
真該在這把你斃了
Christ!
天！
Let's go up the bell tower.
我們到鐘樓樓頂去吧
Be quiet up there this time of evening.
晚上的這個時候那裡應該沒人了
Let's go up there.
我們上去吧
Yeah. Canadians.
嗯，加拿大人
I feel a bit bad. They didn't kill John Lennon, did they?
我有點內疚了 不是他們殺死的約翰·列儂 ，是吧？
Anyway, supposed to turn up to court here in two days.
不管怎麼樣了 兩天後就得去對簿公堂了
Are you going to turn up?
你會去嗎？
Don't know.
不知道
What have I got to stay for really?
我為什麼要駐足停留呢？
The most beautiful woman
這有在你灰暗的人生中
you've ever seen
你所見過的
in all of your stupid life.
最漂亮的女人
The tower is closed this evening.
鐘樓晚上不開
No way. It's supposed to be open till 7:00.
不是吧，開到七點的啊
The tower is usually open until 7:00.
以前是到七點
Yesterday an American had a heart attack up the tower.
昨天有個美國人在上面心臟病突發
Today the tower is closed.
所以今天關的早
Here, cranky, here's 100 for you. We're only gonna be 20 minutes.
來，小子，給你100 我們就上去20分鐘
The tower is closed this evening.
今天晚上鐘樓不開
Understand, Englishman?
明白了，英國佬？
Jimmy, I've been wanting to say
吉米，我一直想說
I'm really sorry for karate-chopping you the other night.
很抱歉那天用空手道打了你
That was way out of order.
那實在是太過份了
You know, Ray, I'd find it easier to believe and forgive you, somehow,
你知道的，雷，如果你們兩個
if the two of you weren't laughing straight in my fucking face!
別當著我的面偷笑 我會更樂意原諒你的
It's for the goddamn movie, man.
這樣都是為了那部狗屁電影
It is a nice town, Harry.
這是個很好的地方，哈里
I'm glad I got to see it.
我很高興我來過這
I didn't mean to be taking the piss out of it being a fairytale place.
我不是虛與委蛇的說 這是個神話般的地方
It is a fairytale place.
這就是個神話般的地方
It really is. Hmm.
- 真的是 - 嗯
It's just a shame it's in Belgium, really.
只是可惜是在比利時
But then you figure if it wasn't in Belgium, if it was somewhere good,
但是你也知道如果不是在比利時 而是在其他著名的地方的話
there'd be too many people coming to see it. It would spoil the whole thing.
就會有太多的人來這 這樣就會毀了它的
Well, I'm glad I got to see it
喔，我很高興來過這
before I died.
在我死之前
What are you doing?
你這是幹什麼？
What are you fucking doing?
你他媽的這是幹什麼？
I'm not fighting anymore, Harry.
我不會再抵抗了，哈里
All right, then I'm blowing your fucking head off.
那好，那我就一槍把你崩了
Don't come over all Gandhi. What are you fucking doing?
別學什麼甘地了，你這算哪門子事？
Ken, stop messing about, please.
肯，別磨嘰了，好吧
Pick up your gun. I know I'm going to beat you anyway
拿起槍，不管怎麼樣我都會殺你的
'Cause you're a spaz, but... Harry,
- 你是個笨蛋，不過… - 哈里
I'm totally in your debt.
我欠你的
The things that have gone between us in the past,
我們之間的情誼
I love you unreservedly for all that.
因為所有的那些我無條件的愛你
What?
什麼？
For your integrity.
你的正直
For your honor.
你的榮耀
I love you.
我愛你
The boy had to be let go.
你應該放過他
The boy had to be given a chance.
你應該給他一個機會
And if to do that, I had to say, " Fuck you, and fuck what I owe you,
如果你執意要殺他，那我只能說 「去你媽的，去他媽我欠你的
"and fuck everything that's gone on between us," then that's what I had to do.
去他們我們之間的情誼」 我只能這麼做
But I'm not fighting you.
但是我不會和你爭鬥
And I accept, totally, everything you've got to do.
我接受，全部接受你的懲罰
I accept it. Totally.
我接受，全部接受
Oh, yeah?
哦，是嗎？
Yeah.
嗯
Well, you say all that fucking stuff, I can't fucking shoot you now, can I?
喔，你說了那麼多，我他媽的就不能開槍了，是吧？
It's entirely up to you, Harry.
那是你的自由，哈里
It's entirely your call.
那看你自己的選擇
All I'm saying is I'm not fighting.
只是我，絕對不會反抗
Oh, you fucking cunt!
哦，你個混蛋！
Look, I'm not gonna do nothing to you
聽著，我不可能因為你他媽像
just 'Cause you're standing about like Robert fucking Powell.
羅伯特·波威爾一樣大義凜然 我就不會為難你
Like who? Like Robert fucking Powell
- 像誰？ - 像羅伯特·波威爾
out of Jesus of fucking Nazareth!
《拿撒勒的耶穌》飾演耶穌的那個
My fucking leg!
我的腿
The psycho dwarf turns out to just be a loveable little schoolboy,
最後發現那個患精神病的矮子 只是一個可愛的小學生
and it's all some kind of Boschian nightmare.
所有的一切只是噩夢而已
Kiss my ass!
真他媽無聊！
I guess at least there weren't any black people involved, eh, Jimmy?
我猜裡面沒有黑人吧，呃，吉米？
I wasn't...
我不是..
I wasn't talking about...
我不是在說…
There's gonna be a war between all the blacks and all the whites.
所有的黑人和白人將會有一場戰爭的
And all the black midgets and all the white midgets,
所有的黑矮人和白矮人也會有
which would actually be really good.
這樣可棒極了
That's just cocaine.
我那時不是嗑了可卡因嘛
He didn't even want the Vietnamese on his side!
他甚至不想要越南人在他這一邊
That's just cocaine.
我那時嗑了可卡因而已
Listen, we're filming down by the pointy building tonight.
聽著，我們今晚在那個尖尖的建築那拍
It might actually be good for once.
可能會很好玩哦
You guys should come along.
你們一起去吧
We... I think we're just gonna have a quiet one tonight, Jimmy.
我們…我想我們今晚需要一個安靜點的地方，吉米
That's how it is!
我明白了！
In another life.
不同的世界啊！
They're great, aren't they?
他們是好人，對吧？
You didn't. You didn't!
你沒有！你沒有！
Mr. Waters? Mr. Waters?
沃特斯先生？沃特斯先生？
Who's that? It's Eirik.
- 誰？ - 埃裡克
The blind boy? Yeah.
- 那個瞎子？ - 嗯
Yes.
嗯
What do you fucking want?
你想幹嘛？
The guy you're looking for,
你要找的那個人
the guy Ray, he's downstairs at the bar.
那個雷，他在樓下的酒吧裡
I'm sorry, Ken.
很抱歉，肯
But you can't kill a kid and expect to get away with it.
但是你不可能殺死一個小孩 卻能逍遙法外
You just can't.
不可能
Where? To the left when you come out.
- 在哪？ - 出去之後左走
The bar to the left.
酒吧的左邊
Ken!
肯！
Ken! Ken!
肯！肯！
Harry's here.
哈里來了
What?
什麼？
Take
拿著
my gun.
我的槍
Ken?
肯？
Where's my gun?
我的槍在哪？
I'm gonna die now, I think.
我快要死了吧，我想
Oh, Ken!
哦，肯！
Jesus!
天哪！
Mr. Blakely said you had left.
布萊克裡先生說你已經走了啊
I need the key to the room right now.
我要房間的鑰匙，快點
Quickly, now!
快點！
And you gotta go home right now. It's very, very dangerous here.
你現在趕緊回家去 這裡非常非常危險
All right? Go home! Right now! Okay.
- 好吧？回家去！快點！ - 好的
MARIE: No, I won't let you up there! Put that gun away, right now!
不，我不會讓你上去的！ 把槍放下，快點！
HARRY: Lady, get out of my fucking way, please.
女士，請你他媽讓開！
No, I won't. I won't get out of your way.
不，我不讓
You'll have to go through me.
要過去先殺了我吧
Well, obviously, I'm not gonna through you, am I, with a baby and that?
喔，很明顯，我不會殺你 你懷孕了，不是嗎？
I'm a nice person.
我是個好人
But could you just get out of the fucking way, please?
但是他媽的請你讓開好吧？
Marie!
瑪麗！
Just let him come up, it's okay.
讓他上來吧，沒事的
Harry, swear not to start shooting until she's left the hotel.
哈里，答應我她離開了這 我們再開打
I swear not to start shooting till she's left the hotel. I totally swear.
我發誓她走了我才會開槍 我鄭重的發誓
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
喔，我哪都不去
This is my hotel.
這是我的旅館
So you can fuck off!
你給我滾！
I suppose you've got a gun up there? Yeah.
- 你拿到槍了吧？ - 嗯
Then what are we gonna do? We can't stand here all night.
那你準備怎麼辦？ 我們不可能這樣站一晚上吧
Why don't you both put your guns down and go home?
你們兩位幹嘛不一起把槍放下 然後回家去？
Don't be stupid. This is the shootout.
別傻了，這是槍戰
Harry, I've got an idea. What?
- 哈里，我有個主意 - 什麼？
My room faces onto the canal, right?
我的房間下面是條運河，是吧？
I'm gonna go back to me room, jump into the canal,
我回我的房間，跳進運河
see if I can swim to the other side and escape.
看我能不能游到對面然後逃走
Right. If you go outside and round the corner,
- 好 - 你可以出去在那個角上
you can shoot at me from there and try and get me.
朝我開槍，看能不能殺了我
That way, we leave this lady and her baby out of the whole, entire thing.
這樣，我們就不會把那位女士 和她的孩子牽扯進來了
Do you completely promise to jump into the canal?
你發誓一定跳進運河？
I don't want to run out there, come back in 10 minutes
我看不想跑出去，10分鐘之後回來
and find you fucking hiding in a cupboard.
卻發現你躲在壁櫥裡
I completely promise, Harry.
我發誓，哈里
I'm not gonna risk having another little kid die, am I?
我可不想再讓一個小孩死了，對吧？
So, hang on, I go outside, then I go which way, right or left?
等等，我出去，然後往哪邊走？ 右還是左？
You go right, don't you?
右，對吧？
You can see it from the doorway! It's a big fucking canal!
你從門口就能看見了！ 他媽的那麼大一運河
All right. Jesus! I've only just got here, haven't I?
好的，天！我剛從那過來的，是吧？
Okay. On a count of "one, two, three, go," okay?
好的，數「1，2，3」，好吧？
Okay.
好
What? Who says it?
誰來數？
Oh, you say it.
哦，你數吧
You guys are crazy.
你們兩個都瘋了
Are you ready? Ready.
- 好了嗎？ - 好了
Set? Set.
- 預備？ - 預備
One, two, three, go!
1，2，3，開始！
Keep driving!
接著開！
No way. You're way too far away.
不可能，你離我太遠了
The little boy.
那個小孩
That's right, Ray.
對，雷
Oh.
哦
I see.
我明白了
No, Harry.
不，哈里
He's not...
他不是…
You've got to stick to your principles.
你得遵守規則不是
RAY. ; There's a Christmas tree somewhere in London
在倫敦，有一棵聖誕樹
with a bunch of presents underneath it that'll never be opened.
下面有好多禮物 卻永遠沒人去打開它們了
And I thought, "If I survive all this, I'll go to that house,
我就想「如果我能活下去 我會到他家去
"apologize to the mother there,
向他母親道歉
"and accept whatever punishment she chose for me."
然後接受懲罰，不管那是什麼
Prison, death, it didn't matter.
坐牢，槍斃，都無所謂了
Because at least in prison and at least in death, you know,
因為不管是坐牢還是槍斃，你知道
I wouldn't be in fucking Bruges.
我都不會在布魯日了」
But then, like a flash, it came to me, and I realized,
忽然之間，我又意識到
"Fuck, man, maybe that's what Hell is.
靠，也許這就是地獄
"The entire rest of eternity spent in fucking Bruges!"
我剩下的日子都得他媽 在布魯日呆著了
And I really, really hoped I wouldn't die.
我真的，真的很希望我不會死
I really, really
我真的，真的很希望我能活著